Guide to the Jacob Gould Schurman papers, 1867-1942 [1986].
Schurman, Jacob Gould papers, 1867-1942 [1986].
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Jacob Gould Schurman papers, 1867-1942 [1986].
3-4-6
Jacob Gould, Schurman 1854-1942.
8.3 cubic ft.; 55 reels microfilm; 1 tape recording; 10 oversize map case folders.
Correspondence, photographs, clippings, microfilm, and ephemera
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Schurman papers consist of correspondence, addresses, photographs, testimonials, diplomas, certificates, newspaper clippings, printed material, and records of the New York Constitutional Convention (1915). The material listed covers Schurman's career as a teacher, college president, and diplomat; the majority of the papers involve his role in national and foreign affairs. His views on American imperialism are reflected in letters to President McKinley, David Starr Jordan, David J. Hill, and John Hay. Schurman's later correspondence with Theodore Roosevelt, Charles F. Adams, Carl Schurz, Charles W. Eliot, and Sergio Osmena show his interest in the Philippine Islands and their eventual independence. His active interest in politics, the problems of peace and the League of Nations, and his diplomatic activities are discussed in correspondence with William Howard Taft, Charles Evans Hughes, Elihu Root, Henry Lane Wilson, Henry Cabot Lodge, James Wadsworth, Joseph Foraker, and Frank Kellogg, including comments on Gustav Stresemann, German politics, and the German economy. Includes addresses and other material on Germany, the Far East, and U.S. foreign policy after Schurman's retirement in 1930. Also personal and family correspondence including letters to Professor William John Alexander about his thoughts on religion and his stay at Heidelberg University; letters to his daughters, Helen and Barbara; and transcriptions and photocopies of other letters.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Schurman family was of Dutch descent, and after flourishing in America, was forced to leave New York for Canada during the American Revolution due to its Loyalist sympathies. Born on May 22, 1854 in Freetown, Prince Edward Island, Canada, Jacob Gould Schurman early in his life demonstrated himself as a talented student, and he earned a series of scholarships. After attending the Prince of Wales College and Acadia College in Nova Scotia, he graduated in 1877 from the University of London with first class honors in mental and moral science, attending other lectures at Manchester New College on mental and moral philosophy and religion. He then studied philosophy for a year at Edinburgh while simultaneously studying in London, earning there an M.A. and D.Sc. with distinction, in 1878. Schurman then studied philosophy in Berlin, at Göttingen, and at the University of Heidelberg. While in Berlin he made the acquaintance of Andrew Dickson White, ambassador to Germany and president of Cornell University
In 1880, Schurman returned to North America to become a professor of English literature at Acadia College. From 1882 to 1886 he was professor of English literature, rhetoric, and metaphysics at Dalhousie University.
From Dalhousie, Schurman moved to Cornell University, where he served as a professor of Christian ethics and moral philosophy. His work at Cornell came under the close sponsorship of University Trustee and benefactor Henry W. Sage. When in 1890 Sage endowed the School of Philosophy, Schurman was appointed dean. Two years later, in 1892, as Charles Kendall Adams ended his troubled presidency of Cornell, Schurman became the third president of the university, serving until 1920.
Schurman's stewardship of Cornell was characterized by the extensive growth of the University's facilities, and its shift from a privately endowed institution to its current coalition of state and private funding. Throughout the twenty eight years of his presidency, Schurman was a proponent of academic freedom and an advocate of a generally liberal intellectual atmosphere on campus. During his presidency of Cornell, Schurman's scholastic pursuits and writings gradually moved away from philosophy and toward public and philanthropic endeavors. He became a presence in the national and New York State Republican Parties, identifying himself with Charles Evans Hughes, and it was thought that only his Canadian birth prevented him from seriously pursuing the presidency of the United States. While still president of Cornell, Schurman served as chairman of a commission examining social and political life in the Philippines in 1899. In 1912 and 1913, he was minister to Greece and Montegnegro during the Balkan Wars. In America, he served as vice president of the New York State Constitutional Convention in 1915, and was a member of the New York State Food Commission in 1917-1918
Upon leaving Cornell, Schurman went to Japan and the Far East, and then served as minister to China from 1921 to 1925, a time of war and great political upheaval. His pattern of finding himself in tumultuous times continued when he served as the American ambassador to Germany from 1925 to 1930. The honor that was due him for his efforts to rebuild the University of Heidelberg translated into popularity with the centrist forces in the Weimar Republic.
After a lectureship in California and additional travels and writing on international subjects, Schurman died in New York in 1942.
BIOGRAPHICAL APPRECIATION
Schurman and Heidelberg
February 8, 1986 was celebrated as Schurman Day at the University of Heidelberg. More than forty years after his death, Jacob Gould Schurman's influence was still strong at the university he had cherished as no other. Schurman arrived in Heidelberg 1878, and it was there that his intellectual foundations found their bearings. Philosophy in Germany in the late eighteenth century was a cultural passion. Innovation and intense activity in philosophical dialogue combined with the spectral setting at Heidelberg influenced Schurman forever. At the age of seventy three, in 1928, Schurman undertook to acknowledge his appreciation to the university by leading an effort to raise funds for its growth. In many of his speeches concerning the campaign, he acknowledged that he had gone to Heidelberg, in part, because there was no American university that could provide the kind of passionate liberal learning and moral philosophy for which he yearned. Schurman first obtained from John D. Rockefeller $200,000, and eventually raised almost $600,000. The monies were used to erect a new lecture hall, called the "New University." Schurman's passionate crusade of vigorous fundraising was a fervid moment in a otherwise decorous and sober public life. By an abiding association of Heidelberg and his own intellectual flourishing, sentiment combined with his usual practical skill to result in the marshalling of forces and finances to noble effect
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Schurman papers consist of correspondence, addresses, photographs, testimonials, diplomas, certificates, newspaper clippings, printed material, and records of the New York Constitutional Convention (1915). The material listed covers Schurman's career as a teacher, college president, and diplomat; the majority of the papers involve his role in national and foreign affairs. His views on American imperialism are reflected in letters to President McKinley, David Starr Jordan, David J. Hill, and John Hay. Schurman's later correspondence with Theodore Roosevelt, Charles F. Adams, Carl Schurz, Charles W. Eliot, and Sergio Osmena show his interest in the Philippine Islands and their eventual independence. His active interest in politics, the problems of peace and the League of Nations, and his diplomatic activities are discussed in correspondence with William Howard Taft, Charles Evans Hughes, Elihu Root, Henry Lane Wilson, Henry Cabot Lodge, James Wadsworth, Joseph Foraker, and Frank Kellogg, including comments on Gustav Stresemann, German politics, and the German economy. Includes addresses and other material on Germany, the Far East, and U.S. foreign policy after Schurman's retirement in 1930. Also personal and family correspondence including letters to Professor William John Alexander about his thoughts on religion and his stay at Heidelberg University; letters to his daughters, Helen and Barbara; and transcriptions and photocopies of other letters.
Items about Jacob Gould Schurman Day (February 8, 1986) at the University of Heidelberg include an typescript copy of an address by John R. Silber, President of Boston University. Also, a cassette copy of a recording of Schurman's speech given when he departed as ambassador from Germany.
Also included is a notebook of photographs and correspondence concerning Schurman Hall at the University of Heidelberg, dedicated in memory of Jacob Gould Schurman.
Silver box presented to Jacob Gould Schurman by the staff of the embassy in China on his appointment as Minister to Germany, donated by Richard W. Kehrt in loving memory of his wife Suzanne D. Schurman, granddaughter of Jacob Gould Schurman.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Schurman, Jacob Gould,1854-1942.; Adams, Charles Francis, 1835-1915.; Alexander, William John.; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926.; Foraker, Joseph Benson, 1846-1917.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923.; Hay, John.; Hill, David J.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.; Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924.; McKinley, William, 1843-1901.; Osmeäna, Sergio, 1878-1961.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.; Schurman, Barbara.; Schurman, Helen.; Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906.; Silber, John Robert, 1926-; Stresemann, Gustav, 1878-1929.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Wadsworth, James.; Wilson, Henry Lane.; Cornell University.; League of Nations.; New York (State). Constitutional Convention, 1915.; United States. Philippine Commission.; Universitèat Heidelberg.
Subjects:
War of 1912-1913.; Education.; International relations.; Religion.; Diplomats.; Ambassadors.
Places:
United States--Diplomatic and consular service.; China.; Philippines.; Greece.; Montenegro (Yugoslavia); Germany.; Balkan Peninsula--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Letterpress copybooks.; Photographs.; Diplomas.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Digital Guides:
There are two additional digital guides for this collection containing information not seen on this page. They are available by following the links below.
1. Information contained in the guide below and a name index is available here. 2 MB PDF file.
2. An additional extensive index to the letterbooks is available here. 9 MB PDF file.
PROVENANCE
The letterbooks and correspondence of the Jacob Gould Schurman papers derive from the Office of the President of Cornell University, and for many years were in the care of Cornell University Library. Other correspondence, photographs, testimonials and social correspondence, and personal and family letters were transferred to the Department of Manuscripts and University Archives at various times from Schurman family members, notably including Judge Jacob G. Schurman, Lydia Schurman Godfrey, and G. Michael McHugh. Some Schurman letters have on several occasions over the years been transferred from the Department of Rare Books of Cornell University Library. Other contributors have included John R. Silber, and the Dewitt Historical Society of Ithaca, New York.
RELATED MATERIAL
The National Archives holds microfilm of Schurman's diplomatic and ministerial correspondence from his ambassadorships and activities as minister and commissioner.
In addition to the following list of collections in the main or in large part concerned with Schurman, reference to and discussion about him can be found in numerous papers of Cornell University faculty members, administrators, trustees, students, and Ithaca residents. Morris Bishop's A History of Cornell is perhaps the most extensive account of Schurman's presidency and influence.
In the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections at Cornell University Library
#700-31
"The Reluctant Expansionist" by Judy Feldman.
#700-85
"An Intellectual's Religious Quest: Jacob Gould Schurman, 1854-1942" by Lydia Godfrey Schurman.
#700-30
"Jacob Gould Schurman and the Cornell Tradition" by Eugene Hotchkiss, III.
#2612
United States Commission to the Philippine Islands, State Department Records, 1899-1900 (microfilm)
#2770
James M. McHugh papers
#35-4-42
Typhoid Fever Epidemic records
#1900
Frank E. Gannett papers
#47-4-1290
Cornell University Presidential Inauguration Programs
#37-5-2534
Solomon Stanwood Menken Scrapbook
#3-4-122
Carnegie Foundation records (also on microfilm)
Other Books and Articles in Cornell University Library
"Government of Dependencies; an essay" With an introduction by Jacob Gould Schurman, by Sir George Cornewall Lewis.
"The History of Heidelberg University" by Gerhard Hinz.
"Jacob Gould Schurman and State Aid to Cornell University, 1892- 1904" by Jeffrey Randolph Fleischmann.
"Memoirs of Victor Buencamino."
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence, 1877-1942
Incoming Correspondence, 1879-1942
Boxes 1-6
Microfilmed on reels 2-7
Letterbooks, 1889-1921
Microfilmed on reels 8-47
Family Correspondence, 1877-1939
Box 16, 17
Microfilmed on reel 53
Series II. Schurman Articles, Speeches, And Books, 1875-1941
Boxes 7-13
Microfilmed on reels 48-51
Series III. Subject Files, 1881-1940, [1986]
Boxes 14-15
Microfilmed on reel 52
Series IV. Clippings, 1892-1942
Box 39
Microfilmed on reels 55 and 56
Series V. Photographs, 1867-1942
Boxes 18-29
Microfilmed on reel 54
Series VI. Proclamations, Protocol And Social Material, Testimonials, And Ephemera, 1878-1939
Boxes 30-38 Microfilmed on reels 53, 55, 56)
Series VII. Map Case items and Tape Recording
Map cases E5, N3, Y18, KK6
Tape recording tr5185a
Series VIII. Microfilm
Series IX. Additional Memorabilia
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence, 1877-1942
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1879-1942 (Reel 2-7)
    Letters received by Schurman range from the time of his student days abroad to notes of condolence received by family members upon his death in 1942. A few letters from Schurman to his recipients were retained in this file. Schurman's correspondents in this selection of letters include major philosophers, Presidents of the United States, family members, mentors, colleagues, students, admirers, and international diplomats and heads of state. The entire breadth of Schurman's professional careers and aspects of his family life are illuminated in these letters. His fundraising for the University of Heidelberg is clearly outlined, as well as his strong advocacy of Philippine independence, his close interest in German political affairs, and his personal relationship with several international scholars and political leaders. Other topics include the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, and international anti-imperialist movements. Philippine, Chinese, Japanese, and German affairs figure prominently in these letters. The letters from his presidency refer to Cornell University administration and relations with the Trustees. Major correspondents include William McKinley, Theodore Roosevelt, William Howard Taft, Warren G. Harding, Woodrow Wilson, Calvin Coolidge, David Starr Jordan, Sao-ke Alfred Sze, Gustav Stresemann, Frank H. Hiscock, Mynderse Van Cleef, Johannes Hoops, John D. Rockefeller, George Eastman, Sergio Osmeña, Franklin D. Roosevelt, and Andrew Seth Pringle-Pattison.
    - Seth Pringle-Pattison, Andrew; Zeller, Edward., 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Zeller, Edward; James, William; Martineau, James., 1884-1888 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Jordan, David Starr. Inauguration of Jacob Gould Schurman as President of Cornell University., 1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Carnegie, Andrew; Huffcut, E. W.; Wilson, Woodrow; Wheeler, Benjamin Ide; de Bordes, Andres Bezia; Bradley, M. E.; Sibley, Hiram W., 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Choate, Joseph H.; White, Horace., 1894-1895 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Norton, C. E.; Tyler, Moses Coit; White, Andrew Dickson., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Angell, James B.; Foraker, Joseph B.; Smith, Goldwin; Dabney, Charles W.; McKinley, William; Morrill, Justin S., 1897 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - McKinley, William; Smith, Goldwin., 1898 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - McKinley, William; Hay, John., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - China; Hong Kong; Japan; Formosa. Letters from Schurman., Feb. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Philippines; Hong Kong; United States Commission to the Philippines. Letter from Schurman., Mar. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Hill, David J.; Morrill, James S.; Morrill, Justin S. Philippines; United States Commission to the Philippines., Apr. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hay, John. United States Commission to the Philippines., May-Aug. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dewey, George; McKinley, William; Hill, David J. Philippines., Aug.-Sept. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Reid, Whitelaw; Root, Elihu; Anderson, Thomas M.; Hill, David J., Oct.-Dec. 1899 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Buck, A. E.; Roosevelt, Theodore; Taft, William Howard; Moses, Bernard; Hay, John; McKinley, William; Corson, Hiram. Porto Rico., Jan.-Aug. 1900 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Roberts, Isaac P.; Lopez, Sixto; White, Horace. Philippines., Oct.-Dec. 1900 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - White, Andrew Dickson; Foraker, Joseph B.; Roosevelt, Theodore; Harrison, Benjamin; White, Horace; Smith, Goldwin; Corson, Eugene R.; Dennis, L. M., 1901 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Mead, Edwin D.; Warren, Winslow; Howells, William Dean; Parkhurst, C. H.; Lodge, Henry Cabot. Philippines., Jan.-Feb. 1902 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Hill, David J.; Milholland, J. E.; Carnegie, Andrew; Holt, Hamilton. Philippines., Mar.-Apr. 1902 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Schurz, Carl; Smith, Goldwin; Adams, Charles F.; Roosevelt, Theodore; Holt, Hamilton; Eliot, Charles W.; Lopez, Sixto; Schurz, Carl; Carus, Paul; Mead, Edwin D.; Lodge, Henry Cabot. Philippines; Religious Parliament Extension., May-June 1902 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Adams, Charles F.; Roosevelt, Theodore; Milholland, J. E.; Hazard, Caroline; Remsen, Ira; Morton, Levi Parsons. Philippines., July-Dec. 1902 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Frankenheimer, John; Lowell, Josephine Shaw; Finch, Francis M.; Huffcut, E. W.; Hay, John; Barnes, Alfred C.; Smith, Goldwin. Philippines., Jan.-June 1903 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore; Winslow, Erving; Burr, George Lincoln; Jones, George W.; Titchener, E. M.; Comstock, John Henry; Hull, Charles H.; Bristol, George P.; Wait, Lucien Augustus; Bailey, Liberty Hyde; Hay, John; James, William. New England Anti-Imperialist League; Philippines., July-Dec. 1903 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Blair, Charles H.; Hay, John; Sibley, Hiram W.; Park, Roswell (photocopy). Panama; Philippines., Jan.-Feb. 1904 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Foraker, Joseph B.; Lowell, Josephine Shaw; Ordway, E. W.; Taft, William Howard. Philippines; Philippine Independence Committee., Mar.-Apr. 1904 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore; Ordway, E. W. Philippines., May 1904 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore; Lowell, J. S., June-July 1904 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Bryce, James; Chambers, Julius; Aso, Shozo. New England Anti-Imperialist League., Sept.-Dec. 1904 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Ordway, E. W.; Lowell, J. S.; White, Horace; Shepard, Charles Sidney; Fiske, Willard; McGraw-Fiske, Jennie; Sage, William H. Philippine Independence Committee; Filipino Progress Association; Philippines; Sage Memorial Chapel., Jan.-Mar. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bryan, William J.; Bennett, Philo Sherman; Looz-Block, Édouard Albert Benoît de (photocopy); Holmes, Oliver Wendell; Choate, Joseph H.; Laurier, Wilfred; Smith, Goldwin; Taft, William Howard., Apr.-Dec. 1905 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray; Bristol, George P. Graduate Dept., Jan.-Feb. 1906 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Winslow, Erving; Rice, James E.; Choate, Joseph H.; Root, Elihu; Eccles, R. M.; Smith, Goldwin; Roosevelt, Theodore; Barraclough, S. Henry; Hughes, Charles E.; Preuss, Else. Anti-Imperialist League., Mar.-Nov. 1906 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - White, Horace; Eliot, Charles W.; Bryce, James. Philippines; St. John's College, Shanghai., Jan.-Mar. 1907 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Rhys, John; Cowie, William; Huffcut, E. W.; Birdseye, Charles F.; Bryce, James; De Majumdar, Indu Bhushan; Hughes, Charles E., Apr.-Dec. 1907 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Hughes, Charles E.; Foraker, Joseph B.; Day, James R. Anti-Imperialist League., Jan.-Feb. 1908 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Hughes, Charles E.; Foraker, Joseph B., Mar.-Apr.1908 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Nabuco, Joaquim; Taft, William Howard; Smith, T. Guilford; Foraker, Joseph B.; Bryce, James., June-Nov. 1908 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Swain, Joseph; Tong-Shoap; Smith, Goldwin., Dec. 1908 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - MacLean, George E. Society for Ethical Culture., Jan. 1909 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Liu, Ting-Tsing; Ho, Yoh-Sze; Foraker, Joseph B.; Van Dyke, Henry; Hughes, Charles E.; Stanton, Theodore., Feb.-Aug. 1909 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Fraser, A. Campbell; Hill, Henry W. Republican State Committee (New York)., Sept.-Dec. 1909 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hiscock, Frank H.; Craig, John; Peary, Robert Edwin; Smith, Goldwin; Van Cleef, Mynderse., Jan.-Feb. 1910 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Bryce, James; Cavanaugh, John; Rowlee, W. W.; Boshart, C. Fred; Hiscock, Frank H. Committee on Student Affairs., Mar.-May 1910 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Van Cleef, Mynderse., May-July 1910 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Vikuchi, D.; Taft, William Howard; Hiscock, Frank H.; Russell, Isaac; Treman, Charles E.; White, Horace; Wilson, Woodrow; Greeley, Horace; Foraker, Joseph B. Horace Greeley Memorial Committee., Oct.-Nov. 1910 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Foraker, Joseph B.; Taft, William Howard., Dec. 1910 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Schurman, Robert; Van Dyke, Henry; Anderson, William F.; Foraker, Joseph B.; Taft, William Howard; Bey, Haldoon., Jan.-May 1911 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Smith, Goldwin; Lee, Sidney; Schurman, Robert., June-Oct. 1911 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Barnes, William; Schurman, Robert; Republican State Committee (NY)., Nov. 1911 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Foraker, Joseph B.; Schurman, Robert., Dec. 1911 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Schiff, Jacob H.; Schurman, Robert; Taft, William Howard; Holt, Hamilton., Jan.-Feb. 1912 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Grosvenor, Gilbert H.; Peary, Robert Edwin; Hilles, Charles D.; Taft, William Howard. Rollins College., Mar. 1912 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Barnes, William; Knox, Philander Chase; Rackemann, Felix; Foraker, Joseph B., Apr. 1912 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Foraker, Joseph B.; Cuyler, Theodore L.; Taft, William Howard., May-June 1912 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Wilson, Woodrow; Taft, William Howard; Adee, Alvey A.; Root, Elihu., July-Dec. 1912 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Taft, William Howard; Wilson, Woodrow; Crane, F. F.; Van Cleef, Mynderse; Williams, Roger B.; Hiscock, Frank H., Jan.-Sept. 1913 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Farwell, J. D.; Hilles, Charles D.; Hughes, Charles E.; Taft, William Howard; Hiscock, Frank H., Oct.-Nov. 1913 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Hiscock, Frank H.; Stimson, Henry L.; Wilson, Woodrow; Bryce, James; Roosevelt, Theodore; Taft, William Howard., Dec. 1913 July 1914 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Hiscock, Frank H.; Parker, Horatio Gilbert George; Addams, Jane; Gage, Simon Henry; Schurman, Major; Adams, Charles F., Aug.-Nov. 1914 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Hiscock, Frank H.; Schurman, Major; Mischef, Hadgi; Lima, Casimiro Eugenio Amoroso; Willcox, Walter F.; Hammond, William A.; Seth, James; Taft, William Howard; Blatch, Harriot Stanton., Dec. 1914 Apr. 1915 (Box 2, Folder 30)